

732.485.1188 michael.emmanuel732@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/michael-emmanuel

#### **ABOUT**

An energetic software engineer with 7+ years experience developing robust code for high-volume businesses. Experienced working on various projects in differing capacities on the frontend, backend, database management and cloud. An enthusiastic team player and creative thinker who has experience working as a software engineer, tester and presenter.

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

**Kyndryl (IBM)** | Remote Sept 2022 – Current Senior Software Engineer

- Architect highly scalable solutions for businesses
- Build serverless components with Node.js & AWS
- Prepare and demo products, prepare and present slide decks of project

Capital Rx | Remote May 2021 – Aug 2022 Senior Full Stack Developer

- Designed, modified and implemented serverless backend APIs with AWS Lambda functions
- Created modular reusable EC2s and CI/CD pipelines with IaC, improve microservices
- Created, tested and maintained REST APIs and handled Protected Health Information (PHI)

**CANVII - UpWork** | Remote Aug 2020 – May 2021 *Freelance Senior Web Developer* 

- Created and maintained frontend and backend components using TypeScript React & NodeJS
- Created server-side APIs in NodeJS and AWS
- Created GraphQL APIs and backend controllers to perform business logic
- Owned scope of project from start to completion

ADP | Remote Feb 2018 – Aug 2020 Application Developer

- Used NodeJS to create PCI-DSS compliant event-driven microservices and server-side APIs
- Created and deployed reusable components and micro-services for payroll and HR functions
- Handled Personal Identifiable Information (PII)
- Designed & implemented application specifications

# **EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED**

Rutgers U. | New Brunswick, NJ Nov 2017 – Jan 2018 Frontend Web Developer

- Converted Rutgers homepage from static web pages to responsive React single page application
- Configured API backend for Rutgers University homepage through RESTful programming

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp Oct 2016 – May 2017 Web Developer Immersive Program

- Contributed to open source
- Built applications for non profit
- Participated in Hackathons

Artsy Jewels | Remote Jan 2016 - Sept 2016 Freelance Web Developer

- Created modular reusable components using React, Node, SASS and various libraries
- Defined, identified, collected and organized detailed information relating to UI requirements
- Documented new findings and integrations

AT&T Corp | Piscataway, NJ Nov 2014 – Dec 2015 Software Developer in Test (SDET)

- Built a Testing Framework to automate the testing of manual test cases by creating automation scripts, increased production by 55%
- Documented, tested, and debugged software defects

## **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University | New Brunswick, NJ 2010 - 2014 B.S. Computer Science

## SKILLS

- Excellent and warm communication skills
- Highly organized with strong attention to detail
- Passion for efficiency, AGILE, SCRUM, JIRA
- Postman, Figma, VSCode, Linux, Windows
- PostgreSQL, SQL, TypeScript, Git, Terraform
- Pvthon, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB
- Docker, GraphQL, Jenkins, AWS, Version Control

### **INTERESTS**

Camera work: Photography & PhotoShop

Music: Mixing & Mastering

• Hobbies: Gymnastics & Chess